<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[obsidian]]></title><description><![CDATA[Obsidian digital garden]]></description><link>http://github.com/dylang/node-rss</link><image><url>site-lib/media/favicon.png</url><title>obsidian</title><link/></image><generator>Webpage HTML Export plugin for Obsidian</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 10:05:43 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="site-lib/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 10:05:31 GMT</pubDate><ttl>60</ttl><dc:creator/><item><title><![CDATA[index]]></title><description><![CDATA[Thunder Engine is a versatile open-source game engine designed for the seamless development of both 2D and 3D games. Offering a comprehensive suite of frameworks and tools, Thunder Engine empowers developers to concentrate on the creative aspects of game design, while the engine takes care of routine tasks.The core philosophy behind Thunder Engine is to establish a modular architecture, providing developers with the flexibility to selectively include or exclude modules based on their project requirements. This modular approach ensures that projects remain lightweight, tailored to the specific needs of each development endeavor.Developers can leverage the Thunder Engine API to not only incorporate existing modules but also to create and integrate their own custom modules, enhancing the engine's adaptability to unique game design concepts. Furthermore, Thunder Engine's API facilitates the development of editor modules, empowering developers to streamline and enhance their workflow during the game creation process.In essence, Thunder Engine not only simplifies game development through its wide array of features but also offers a modular and extensible architecture, enabling developers to craft tailored solutions for their gaming projects.
<a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="install" data-href="install" href="basics/install.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Install Thunder Engine</a>
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="start" data-href="start" href="basics/start.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">World Editor</a>
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="features" data-href="features" href="basics/features.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Thunder Engine Features</a>
]]></description><link>basics/index.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">basics/index.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 09:12:28 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[index]]></title><description><![CDATA[
<a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="basics/index" data-href="basics/index" href="basics/index.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Getting Started</a>
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="editor/index" data-href="editor/index" href="editor/index.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">World Editor</a>
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="lighting/index" data-href="lighting/index" href="lighting/index.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Lighting</a>
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="rendering/index" data-href="rendering/index" href="rendering/index.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Graphics Pipeline</a>
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="vfx/index" data-href="vfx/index" href="vfx/index.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Visual Effects (VFX</a>
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="scripting/index" data-href="scripting/index" href="scripting/index.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Scripting</a>
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="reference/index" data-href="reference/index" href=".html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">API Reference</a>
]]></description><link>index.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">index.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 09:11:36 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[start]]></title><description><![CDATA[The World Editor stands as a central game development tool within Thunder Engine, providing an essential platform for collaborative efforts among designers and developers. With the World Editor, teams can seamlessly share projects across different development platforms, employing a unified tool for design and development purposes.Locate the World Editor at the following directory within your Thunder Engine installation:sdk/%version%/%platform%/x86_64/bin/WorldEditor
Here, %version% corresponds to the Thunder Engine version (e.g., 2026.1), and %platform% represents your operating system (windows, linux, or macos).Upon launching the World Editor, you'll be greeted by the Welcome screen, offering the following options:
Open recent projects
Create new projects
Import existing projects
Access news from the Thunder Engine project
<img alt="media/welcome.png" src="basics/media/welcome.png" target="_self">To create a new project, follow these steps:
Click the New button<br>
<img alt="media/new.png" src="basics/media/new.png" target="_self">
In the opened dialog, select a directory where the project will be placed
For importing existing projects, follow these steps:
Click the Import button<br>
<img alt="media/import.png" src="basics/media/import.png" target="_self">
In the opened dialog, select the project file with the .forge extension.
Explore the full capabilities of Thunder Engine and the World Editor by delving into the following resources:
Documentation: Refer to the comprehensive Thunder Engine documentation for in-depth insights and tutorials.
Community Forums: Engage with the Thunder Engine community on forums to exchange ideas, seek advice, and stay updated on the latest developments.
Tutorials: Find step-by-step tutorials to enhance your skills and make the most of the World Editor features.
This section aims to guide you beyond the basics, empowering you to harness the full potential of Thunder Engine for your game development endeavors.]]></description><link>basics/start.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">basics/start.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 07:16:31 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="basics/media/welcome.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="basics/media/welcome.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[install]]></title><description><![CDATA[Thunder Engine consists of a set of frameworks and tools. Thunder Engine has a modular structure so developers are able to choose the exact modules they need.Thunder Engine can be installed in two ways:Using Releases page (Preferable)
To download latest release please follow <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://github.com/thunder-engine/thunder/releases" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://github.com/thunder-engine/thunder/releases" target="_self">this link</a>Building engine from the source<br>Thunder Engine source code is hosted at <a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://github.com/thunder-engine/thunder" target="_self">https://github.com/thunder-engine/thunder</a> and can be obtained in several ways: To get the full developer repository, please use Git utility:
git clone https://github.com/thunder-engine/thunder.git <br>
Or using official GitHub utility: <a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://desktop.github.com/" target="_self">https://desktop.github.com/</a> <br>
To get stable release, please use <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://github.com/thunder-engine/thunder/releases" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://github.com/thunder-engine/thunder/releases" target="_self">Releases page</a> <br>
To get latest developer snapshot, please use this <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://github.com/thunder-engine/thunder/archive/master.zip" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://github.com/thunder-engine/thunder/archive/master.zip" target="_self">link</a> To build Thunder Engine from source on Windows you need to set up an additional environment: <br>Microsoft Visual Studio 2022 or higher (You can download <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://visualstudio.microsoft.com/thank-you-downloading-visual-studio/?sku=Community&amp;rel=15#" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://visualstudio.microsoft.com/thank-you-downloading-visual-studio/?sku=Community&amp;rel=15#" target="_self">Community Edition</a> version for free)
Qt 5.15.2 and QtCreator 17.0.2 After setting up all required software, open "Command Prompt" console, go to the directory with Thunder Engine source code, and run the sequence of commands below. Add Qt framework to PATH. For example:
set PATH=%PATH%;C:\Qt\5.15.2\msvc2015\bin Run build procedure:
qbs setup-toolchains --detect
qbs setup-qt C:\Qt\5.15.2\msvc2022\bin\qmake.exe qt
qbs config defaultProfile qt
qbs build --all-products config:release Install latest XCode
Open a Console application and go to the directory with Thunder Engine source code
<br>Install <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://docs.brew.sh/Installation" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://docs.brew.sh/Installation" target="_self">homebrew</a>
Build Thunder Engine by the sequence of commands below:
export QT_INSTALL_DIR=~/Qt
export QT_VERSION=5.15.2
export QT_BIN=$QT_INSTALL_DIR/$QT_VERSION/clang_64/bin
export PATH=$QT_INSTALL_DIR/Qt Creator.app/Contents/MacOS:$QT_BIN:$PATH
bash ./build/install-qt.sh -d $QT_INSTALL_DIR --version $QT_VERSION qtbase qtmultimedia qtscript qtsvg qtimageformats qtgraphicaleffects qtquickcontrols2 qttools qtxmlpatterns qtdeclarative
wget https://download.qt.io/official_releases/qtcreator/17.0/17.0.2/installer_source/mac_x64/qtcreator.7z
7z x -y -o${QT_INSTALL_DIR} qtcreator.7z
qbs --version
qbs setup-toolchains --detect
qbs setup-qt $QT_BIN/qmake qt-brew
qbs install --all-products config:release profile:qt-brew (Optional) To build Thunder Engine for iOS and tvOS, please run additional commands below:qbs resolve config:release profile:xcode-iphoneos-arm64
qbs install --all-products config:release profile:xcode-iphoneos-arm64
qbs resolve config:release profile:xcode-appletvos-arm64
qbs install --all-products config:release profile:xcode-appletvos-arm64
Open Console, go to the directory with Thunder Engine source code, and run the sequence of commands below:export QT_INSTALL_DIR=~/Qt
export QT_VERSION=5.15.2
export QTCREATOR_VERSION=17.0.2
export QT_BIN=${QT_INSTALL_DIR}/${QT_VERSION}/gcc_64/bin
export PATH="$QT_INSTALL_DIR/Tools/QtCreator/bin:$QT_BIN:$PATH"
bash ./build/install-qt.sh -d $QT_INSTALL_DIR --version ${QT_VERSION} qtbase qtmultimedia qtscript qtsvg qtimageformats qttools qtxmlpatterns qtdeclarative qtgamepad icu
bash ./build/install-qt.sh -d $QT_INSTALL_DIR --version ${QTCREATOR_VERSION} qtcreator
qbs setup-toolchains --detect
qbs setup-qt --detect
qbs config defaultProfile
qbs install --all-products config:release
]]></description><link>basics/install.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">basics/install.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 07:13:58 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[features]]></title><description><![CDATA[
Windows
MacOS X
Linux
Android
iOS
tvOS Module based architecture
Entity Component System based Object Management System
Scene Graph object management approach
MetaObject introspection model for Objects
Event driven Inter Object Communication System Flexible render pipeline
Rendering System Based on Physical Principles
Particle system
Deferred Shading
CookTorance Lighting model
Cascaded Shadow Maps (PSSM)
Frustum culling rendering optimization
SDF Fonts AngelScript script engine (Technical Preview) Animation engine is based on "Animate Everything" principles
Animation state machine 2D/3D Audio engine
Ogg/Vorbis, MP3, WAV file formats support Rigid Body
Bunch of volume colliders and triggers like Sphere, Box, Capsule and more Multi-functional scene editor
Node based material editor with shader converter
Animation graph editor and timeline
Plug-ins mechanism
Resource Management system with bunch of converters
Ready for CI project builder
]]></description><link>basics/features.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">basics/features.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 07:07:40 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[index]]></title><description><![CDATA[When you create a new project or open an existing one, you will find yourself on the main screen.The main screen provides a versatile workspace that developers can customize to suit their specific needs.
This workspace is the central hub where you'll perform various tasks and interact with your project's elements.As you work within the main screen and navigate between these areas, you'll have the tools and resources you need to build, edit, and manage your project effectively.
Feel free to explore the various zones to streamline your workflow and achieve your development goals.The World Editor provides robust tools for managing your workspace, allowing users to tailor it to their specific needs.
Whether you're optimizing your layout, adding or removing widgets, adjusting sizes, or configuring panel arrangements, the Workspace Management feature offers flexibility and customization.Changing Workspaces:
Users can seamlessly switch between different workspaces based on their tasks or preferences.
Each workspace configuration is designed to enhance specific workflows, ensuring a dynamic and efficient development environment.Customizing Widgets:
Add, remove, or rearrange widgets within the workspace to create a setup that suits your workflow.
The ability to customize widgets empowers users to prioritize essential tools and information, promoting a personalized and productive experience.Saving and Loading Workspaces:
The World Editor allows you to save your custom workspace configurations to the disk.
This feature is beneficial for users who have tailored their workspace to specific project requirements or have found an optimal arrangement for their workflow.
Load saved workspaces at any time to maintain a consistent and familiar environment.To manage your workspace:
Navigate to the Window &gt; Workspace menu or a dedicated workspace management interface.
Explore options to change, customize, save, and load workspaces.
<img alt="Workspace" src="editor/media/workspace.png" target="_self">The main screen is divided into several key areas:<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="viewport" data-href="viewport" href="editor/viewport.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Viewport</a>: The viewport is the primary working area where you can view and manipulate project content.
This is where you'll spend most of your time interacting with project assets.<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="properties" data-href="properties" href="editor/properties.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Properties</a>: The properties panel, often located on the right side of the screen, displays detailed information and settings for selected project elements.
You can use this panel to adjust properties and configurations.<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="content" data-href="content" href="editor/content.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Content Browser</a>: This area houses the actual content of your project.
It could be your code, design elements, documents, or any other project-specific data.
You can organize and manage your content from this section.<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="hierarchy" data-href="hierarchy" href="editor/hierarchy.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Hierarchy</a>: The hierarchy panel provides an overview of the structure and organization of your project.
It displays a tree-like representation of project elements, allowing you to navigate and access different parts of your project efficiently.Remember that the specific features and functionalities within each of these areas may vary depending on your project's nature and the software or platform you're using. Refer to the corresponding sections in this documentation for more detailed information on each area's functionality.Explore the documentation sections below to learn more about all components of the user interface and how to make the most of them in your projects.
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="viewport" data-href="viewport" href="editor/viewport.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Viewport</a>
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="properties" data-href="properties" href="editor/properties.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Properties</a>
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="content" data-href="content" href="editor/content.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Content Browser</a>
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="hierarchy" data-href="hierarchy" href="editor/hierarchy.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Hierarchy</a>
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="plugins" data-href="plugins" href="editor/plugins.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Plugin Manager</a>
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="builder" data-href="builder" href="editor/builder.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Building Project</a>
]]></description><link>editor/index.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">editor/index.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 06:31:24 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="editor/media/workspace.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="editor/media/workspace.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[properties]]></title><description><![CDATA[Properties is a tool created for fine-tuning of all object properties (assigned material, texture, color, and many more)<img alt="Properties" src="editor/media/properties.png" target="_self">This editor contains a three main sections:The tree of available properties creates automatically based on introspection of attached Components.
The user is able to add and remove Components from the Actor at any time:
To add a new component please use the "Add Component" button.
To remove component please use the "..." button near the component name.
Based on type the Property editor creates an appropriate widget for each property.Properties editor can also be used to change all import settings for the selected asset.<br><img alt="Asset Properties" src="editor/media/asset_properties.png" target="_self"><br>To activate this mode select any asset in the <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="content" data-href="content" href="editor/content.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Content Browser</a>In this mode additional buttons will appear:]]></description><link>editor/properties.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">editor/properties.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 06:29:29 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="editor/media/properties.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="editor/media/properties.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[viewport]]></title><description><![CDATA[Viewport allows you to add and remove objects on scene, control their positions, rotations and do other basic operations.<img alt="Viewport" src="editor/media/viewport.png" target="_self">The empty game doesn't look fun.
To make it visually appealing we need to add various game objects.
Thunder Engine supports many visual components like 2D sprites and 3D meshes.Now let's create something!
There are a few methods how to placing objects on the scene.<br>
The simplest way is to just drag and drop objects from a <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="content" data-href="content" href="editor/content.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Content Browser</a>.<br><img alt="Create Object" src="editor/media/create_object.gif" target="_self">As you probably noticed the created object is automatically selected.
The selected object has an orange highlight around it.
A developer has the ability to change the color and thickness of a highlighter or completely disable it.
During development, you would need to select objects on the scene.
Just click by LBM on an object and it will be selected.<br><img alt="Toolbar" src="editor/media/editor_tools.png" target="_self">The toolbar contains a various controls to move, rotate and scale selected objects.After an object has been placed on the scene, we may want to move, rotate, or resize it.
Using Toolbar we can do this right in the Viewport.<br><img alt="Move Object" src="editor/media/move.gif" target="_self">
Moving<br><img alt="Rotate Object" src="editor/media/rotate.gif" target="_self">
Rotation<br><img alt="Scale Object" src="editor/media/scale.gif" target="_self">
ScalingHold RMB and move the mouse in the direction you want to look.]]></description><link>editor/viewport.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">editor/viewport.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 06:28:36 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="editor/media/viewport.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="editor/media/viewport.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[plugins]]></title><description><![CDATA[Plugins in the editor provide a powerful mechanism to extend and enhance the functionality of the World Editor.
Whether you want to add custom tools, features, or support for specific asset types, plugins offer a flexible way to tailor the editor to your project's unique requirements.<img alt="Plugin Manager" src="editor/media/plugin_manager.png" target="_self">To install a new plugin in the World Editor, follow these steps:
Navigate to the Edit menu.
Select Plugin Manager.
In the Plugin Manager, Hit + button.
Choose the plugin file or directory.
The World Editor will then load and integrate the plugin into its environment.Once plugins are installed, you can manage them through the Plugin Manager dialog.
To enable or disable a plugin:
Open Plugin Manager.
Locate the plugin in the list.
Toggle the switch next to the plugin to enable or disable it.
Hit "Restart Now" button to restart World Editor to apply changes.
Plugins often come with configuration options to customize their behavior.
Access the plugin configuration settings through the Window &gt; Editor Preferences menu.<br><img alt="Editor Preferences" src="editor/media/editor_preferences.png" target="_self">Here, you can fine-tune the plugin's settings to align with your project's needs.The World Editor supports Embedded Editors, which are specialized tools for specific asset types.
Some plugins may introduce new Embedded Editors to enhance the editing experience.For developers interested in creating their own plugins for the World Editor, a comprehensive plugin development guide is available.
This guide covers the necessary steps, best practices, and APIs to create custom plugins seamlessly integrated into the editor.Plugin management in the World Editor empowers users to extend the editor's capabilities according to project requirements. Whether you're installing pre-built plugins or developing your own, the World Editor's plugin system provides a versatile and efficient way to enhance your game development workflow.Explore the diverse range of plugins available, experiment with customization options, and consider developing your plugins to unlock the full potential of the World Editor for your projects.]]></description><link>editor/plugins.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">editor/plugins.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 06:25:23 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="editor/media/plugin_manager.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="editor/media/plugin_manager.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[hierarchy]]></title><description><![CDATA[The Hierarchy widget is a crucial tool that provides an organized view of the objects placed within your scene and illustrates their relationships.<img alt="Hierarchy" src="editor/media/hierarchy.png" target="_self">When you access the Hierarchy widget, you gain insight into the composition of your scene and how different objects within it are connected.Key features and functionalities of the Hierarchy widget include:The Hierarchy widget is an indispensable tool for managing the complexity of your scene and ensuring that objects are correctly organized and interconnected. Whether you're designing a game, creating a 3D model, or working on a simulation, the Hierarchy widget streamlines your workflow and enhances your ability to navigate and manipulate your project.]]></description><link>editor/hierarchy.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">editor/hierarchy.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 06:21:53 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="editor/media/hierarchy.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="editor/media/hierarchy.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[content]]></title><description><![CDATA[The Content Browser is a central component of your project, offering a convenient way to access and manage the assets available for use.<img alt="Content Browser" src="editor/media/content.png" target="_self">When you open the Content Browser, you'll find a list of all the assets that are at your disposal.
These assets may include images, audio files, documents, and other resources that you can utilize in your project.Using the Content Browser, you can perform various tasks:The Content Browser supports the creation of new assets directly from the context menu. Follow these steps:
Right-click in the Content Browser.
Select the type of asset you want to create (e.g., animation, material, behaviours).
<br><img alt="Asset Creation" src="editor/media/asset_creation.gif" target="_self">This functionality simplifies the asset creation process, allowing you to generate new resources seamlessly within the Content Browser.Effortlessly expand your project's asset library by importing assets through the Content Browser. Follow these steps:
Open a context menu.
Click on the Import New Asset... option.
In the prompted dialog, browse and select the assets you want to import.
The Content Browser is designed to simplify asset management, helping you efficiently work with your project's resources.
Whether you're a designer, developer, or content creator, this tool is invaluable for enhancing your productivity.Make the most of the Content Browser to streamline your workflow and ensure a seamless integration of assets into your project.Users can open assets for viewing and editing by double-clicking on the asset within the Content Browser.
This intuitive feature provides a quick way to inspect and modify assets directly from the Editor.The World Editor comes equipped with a variety of embedded Editors, providing specialized tools for specific asset types.
These Embedded Editors allow for a more in-depth and focused editing experience tailored to each asset category. Additionally, the extensibility of the World Editor is enhanced through the use of [[Plugin Manager]] (`doc_plugin_manager`).
Developers can create custom Plugins to add new features, tools, or support for specific asset types, expanding the capabilities of the World Editor to suit diverse project needs.
The Content Browser allows you to filter assets based on their types.
This feature enables you to focus on specific types of content, making it easier to manage and locate assets.
To filter content by type:
Navigate to the Filter menu in the Content Browser.
Choose the desired content type from the available options.
Now, you can efficiently narrow down your view to only the types of assets you currently need, enhancing your workflow and making content management even more streamlined.]]></description><link>editor/content.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">editor/content.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 06:19:25 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="editor/media/content.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="editor/media/content.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[builder]]></title><description><![CDATA[Once your project is ready, you may want to run it outside the editor for testing or distribution. This section provides guidance on building your project.To build a release binary, you will need a compatible compiler for your platform:
Visual Studio - on Windows
clang - on Linux
XCode - on MacOS
Ensure that the Qbs Builder is accessible by the build environment. You can check this by running the following command in your terminal or command prompt:sdk/%version%/tools/qbs
Alternatively, you can specify the Qbs path in the Editor Preferences:<img alt="QBS Path" src="editor/media/qbs_path.png" target="_self">If you cannot find this tab, please navigate to Window -&gt; Editor Preferences.Now, you are ready to build your project. Follow these steps:
<br>
Click on the Build Project button in the toolbar:
<img alt="Build Project" src="editor/media/build_project.png" target="_self"> After initiating the build process, your game will be placed in a directory. If the build process is successful, you should see a confirmation message:<br> <img alt="Success" src="editor/media/success.png" target="_self">Your game will be copied into the specified build directory.The Builder tool is a console-friendly Continuous Integration (CI) tool that assists developers in creating a game binary and packaging required resources. Locate the Builder tool in the main binary directory near the World Builder executable:sdk/%version%/%platform%/x86_64/bin/Builder
To start the build process, use the following command-line arguments:$ Builder -s project.forge -t target/directory -p platform
Where:
project.forge is the path to your project file.
target/directory is the directory where your game binaries will be placed.
platform specifies the target platform for which your project will be built.
This tool provides flexibility and automation for building your project from the command line, making it suitable for Continuous Integration workflows.Explore these building options based on your preference and project requirements.]]></description><link>editor/builder.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">editor/builder.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 06:15:43 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="editor/media/qbs_path.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="editor/media/qbs_path.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[index]]></title><description><![CDATA[Thunder Engine's lighting features play a crucial role in defining the visual atmosphere of your projects.
Efficient and realistic lighting enhances the overall visual appeal, bringing your scenes to life with dynamic and engaging environments.Physically Based Rendering (PBR): Thunder Engine utilizes PBR to achieve realistic material interactions, allowing for accurate representation of light and materials in the scene.Thunder Engine provides a comprehensive set of lighting features, including: Point Lights: Illuminate specific points in your scene, creating localized light sources that contribute to the overall lighting design. Directional Lights: Simulate sunlight or moonlight with directional lights, casting shadows and defining the primary light direction. Spotlights: Focus light on specific areas, allowing for controlled and dynamic lighting effects. Area Lights: Simulate large light sources with area lights, providing soft and realistic illumination. ]]></description><link>lighting/index.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">lighting/index.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 05:55:59 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[index]]></title><description><![CDATA[Please note that the entire graphics pipeline module is currently in development.
API changes may occur in future releases, and some features may not be fully functional.
Exercise caution when relying on this module in production environments.
Thunder Engine employs a flexible graphics pipeline that allows you to fine-tune the balance between quality and performance on an individual project basis.
This flexibility ensures that you can tailor the graphical settings to meet the specific requirements of your project, providing a versatile solution for achieving the desired visual fidelity while maintaining optimal performance.The graphics pipeline in Thunder Engine is task-based, representing each graphical feature as a task in the pipeline.
This task-oriented approach forms a graph that efficiently processes and renders graphics tasks.
This system allows for a modular and scalable approach to handling graphics tasks, contributing to the engine's adaptability and efficiency in managing complex visual scenarios.Thunder Engine's graphics pipeline is composed of key entities that work together to facilitate rendering tasks efficiently.PipelineContext:
The PipelineContext serves as the execution environment for tasks related to scene rendering.
It provides the runtime context for rendering tasks, coordinating the flow of information between various stages of the rendering process.Pipeline:
A Pipeline in Thunder Engine represents a loadable resource, forming the graphical rendering graph.
Users have the flexibility to customize this graph according to their project requirements.PipelineTask:
Individual atomic units within the graphics pipeline are known as PipelineTask.
These tasks form the building blocks of the rendering graph. When executed by the PipelineContext, each task processes specific aspects of the rendering process.Developers have the ability to extend and customize Thunder Engine's graphics pipeline by creating their own tasks based on the PipelineTask class.
These custom tasks allow for the seamless integration of user-specific rendering functionality, providing a means to enhance or extend the engine's rendering capabilities.Users can edit the graphics pipeline using a dedicated editor, allowing for easy customization of the rendering process.
This integrated editor provides a user-friendly interface for modifying the graphical rendering graph according to the specific needs of the project.AmbientOcclusion:
Handles the Ambient Occlusion effect in 3D scenes.AntiAliasing:
Manages edge smoothing for enhanced visual quality.Bloom:
Creates a glowing effect for bright objects.DeferredLighting:
Used in conjunction with GBuffer for on-screen lighting calculations.GBuffer:
Renders opaque objects on the scene, preserving essential material parameters for later use in other tasks.GuiLayer:
Responsible for rendering the user interface.Reflections:
Calculates material reflection capabilities for realistic image rendering.ShadowMap:
Forms shadow maps for subsequent use in lighting calculations.Translucent:
Handles the rendering of semi-transparent objects on the scene.
Due to the nature of Deferred Shading, these objects must be drawn after lighting calculations.Please note that the availability and functionality of these tasks may be subject to change in future releases.
Refer to the corresponding sections in the documentation for detailed information on each `PipelineTask`.
]]></description><link>rendering/index.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">rendering/index.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 05:55:31 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[camera]]></title><link>rendering/component/camera.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">rendering/component/camera.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 05:51:57 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[overview]]></title><description><![CDATA[Thunder Engine was designed to be modular. This means developers can enable or disable various modules. Developers can also create their own modules to meet their needs.In the Editor, your custom module will be created automatically when you create any Native Behaviour. The Editor will handle all required registrations for your Native Behaviour automatically.The concepts below are common across programming modules.This simple object is a key ring for all related Components.<img alt="media/actor_scheme.png" src="scripting/media/actor_scheme.png" target="_self">Actors are the main objects in the scene. They can be united into hierarchies.<br><img alt="media/hierarhy.png" src="scripting/media/hierarhy.png" target="_self">Components are the lifeblood of any game in Thunder Engine. Components contain information about how your game Actors look or how they interact with other Actors. This information is called Properties and it can be modified in the Editor or directly from the game code.Using the Native version of the API, developers are able to create any type of Components. However, when using the Scriptable API, only the Behaviour type of components is available.A variable that can be changed from the Editor or in-game.<br><img alt="media/properties.png" src="scripting/media/properties.png" target="_self">The Position, Rotation, and Scale are properties of the Transform component.For a specific programming language, please refer to:
<br><a data-href="doc_native_properties" href=".html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">doc_native_properties</a>
When developing gameplay, sometimes it becomes necessary for one object to communicate something to another object. For example, a player has been killed and the "Game Over" window needs to be displayed. There are at least two ways to do this: call the window directly or just send a signal. A listener will catch the signal and react to it.<br><img alt="media/signals_slots.png" src="scripting/media/signals_slots.png" target="_self">For a specific programming language, please refer to:
<br><a data-href="doc_native_signals" href=".html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">doc_native_signals</a>
Any data set that can be loaded from the file system. Some Components, like MeshRender, use Resources. Assets in the Content Browser are a good example of resources.Any Resource must be controlled by the Resource System. This system manages the lifecycle of the resource—loading them on demand and unloading them when they are no longer needed.]]></description><link>scripting/overview.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">scripting/overview.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 12:24:07 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="scripting/media/actor_scheme.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="scripting/media/actor_scheme.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[index]]></title><description><![CDATA[This section covers various aspects related to coding your game in Thunder Engine.Thunder Engine supports a number of programming languages to write your game logic. Each programming language is wrapped into a separate module, and you can include or exclude any of them.The main engine language is C++, and most embedded game objects are written in this programming language. The architecture of the game engine allows developers to mix these modules. However, it is preferable to use only one scripting language in your project.
<a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="overview" data-href="overview" href="scripting/overview.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Overview</a>
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="creating_scripts" data-href="creating_scripts" href="scripting/creating_scripts.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Creating and Using Scripts</a>
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="exporting_variables" data-href="exporting_variables" href="scripting/exporting_variables.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Variables and Property Editor</a>
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="instantiating_prefabs" data-href="instantiating_prefabs" href="scripting/instantiating_prefabs.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Instantiating Prefabs</a>
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="native_introspection" data-href="native_introspection" href="scripting/native_introspection.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Native Introspection</a>
]]></description><link>scripting/index.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">scripting/index.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 12:23:24 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[creating_scripts]]></title><description><![CDATA[Actor behavior is controlled by components attached to them. In addition to the standard components provided by Thunder Engine, developers can add their own components implementing game logic and gameplay features. These components allow triggering game events, responding to user actions, and modifying the properties of other components during gameplay.At the moment, Thunder Engine supports C++ and AngelScript for implementing custom components.Like many other assets, scripts are typically created directly in the engine editor. Within the Content Browser window, simply right-click and select Native Behaviour for C++ code or Angel Behaviour for AngelScript code from the context menu.A new script will be created in the Content Browser window in the folder you selected. You will also be prompted to choose a name for your new component.<img alt="media/new_script.png" src="scripting/media/new_script.png" target="_self">It is good practice to give your component a meaningful name. The name you choose will be used throughout scenes and prefabs, and changing it afterward can be challenging.When you double-click on your new script, it will open in a text editor. By default, the Thunder Engine editor uses its built-in code editor.The initial content will look something like this:#include &lt;nativebehaviour.h&gt;
#include &lt;log.h&gt; class NewNative_Behaviour : public NativeBehaviour { A_REGISTER(NewNative_Behaviour, NativeBehaviour, Components) public: NewNative_Behaviour() { } ~NewNative_Behaviour() { } // Use this to initialize behaviour void start() { } // Will be called each frame. Use this to write your game logic void update() { }
};
class NewAngelBehaviour : Behaviour { // Use this to initialize behaviour void start() override { } // Will be called each frame. Use this to write your game logic void update() override { }
};
The code written in your script will be executed by the engine's internal systems. Currently, we are interested in only two functions:
The start function is called every time an Actor containing our component is created in the scene. It is usually used for initializing internal variables of our component.
The update function is called every frame and is responsible for handling events within the game, where you can write gameplay logic.
Of course, you can create your own functions to simplify working with the code.Now let's write something! Let's add the following code:// Use this to initialize behaviour
void start() { aDebug() &lt;&lt; "Hello world!";
}
// Use this to initialize behaviour
void start() override { debug("Hello world!");
}
After saving your changes, the editor will detect them and start compiling your code. Note that compiling C++ code requires a compiler installed for your system:
Visual Studio for Windows
GCC or Clang for Linux
Xcode for MacOS
No additional actions are required for AngelScript code.After compiling the code, your component will appear in the drop-down menu of the Add Component button:<br><img alt="media/add_component.png" src="scripting/media/add_component.png" target="_self">Let's add it to the selected Actor and start the simulation (Ctrl+G):<br><img alt="media/new_component.png" src="scripting/media/new_component.png" target="_self">If everything was done correctly, you will see a message in the Console Output window:<br><img alt="media/hello_world.png" src="scripting/media/hello_world.png" target="_self">]]></description><link>scripting/creating_scripts.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">scripting/creating_scripts.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 12:22:05 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="scripting/media/new_script.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="scripting/media/new_script.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[index]]></title><description><![CDATA[Thunder Engine's Visual Effects (VFX) capabilities allow you to enhance your projects with stunning and immersive visual elements. From particle systems to shader effects, Thunder Engine provides a range of tools for creating captivating visual experiences.
<a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="editor" data-href="editor" href="vfx/editor.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">VFX Editor</a>
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="custom_modules" data-href="custom_modules" href="vfx/custom_modules.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Creating Custom Modules</a>
]]></description><link>vfx/index.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">vfx/index.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 12:20:30 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[exporting_variables]]></title><description><![CDATA[When you create a script, the editor automatically generates it from a special template. The script will be inherited from a base class: NativeBehaviour for C++ and AngelBehaviour for AngelScript.You can add your own variables and declare them as properties accessible for editing from the Property widget in the engine editor.The code below declares the variable myVariable. When you add the component to any Actor in the Scene and select it, this property will be visible in the Properties editor as a field named "My Variable". The default value "Some Text" will become the value in the property editing window.#include &lt;nativebehaviour.h&gt;
#include &lt;log.h&gt; class NewNative_Behaviour : public NativeBehaviour { A_REGISTER(NewNative_Behaviour, NativeBehaviour, Components) A_PROPERTIES( A_PROPERTY(string, myVariable, NewNative_Behaviour::myVariable, NewNative_Behaviour::setMyVariable) ) private: string m_myVariable = "Some Text"; public: // Use this to initialize behaviour void start() { aDebug() &lt;&lt; "Current value of myVariable =" &lt;&lt; m_myVariable.c_str(); } string myVariable() const { return m_myVariable; } void setMyVariable(string variable) { m_myVariable = variable; }
};
class NewAngelBehaviour : Behaviour { string myVariable = "Some Text"; // Use this to initialize behaviour void start() override { debug("Current value of myVariable=" + myVariable); }
};
Each Actor to which you add your component will have its own value for this property. Note that property declaration in C++ code differs significantly. For more information, refer to the <a data-href="native_introspection" href="scripting/native_introspection.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">native_introspection</a> section.<br><img alt="media/my_variable.png" src="scripting/media/my_variable.png" target="_self">For user convenience, the Property Editor changes the display of your property name by adding spaces between lowercase and uppercase letters. However, in your code, you still need to use the variable name you specified.In addition to basic property types such as string, integer, bool, and others, developers may need properties that reference other objects in the Scene (Transforms, Lights, Actors) or assets (Textures, Meshes, Materials). The code snippet below demonstrates how to achieve this:#include &lt;nativebehaviour.h&gt; class NewNative_Behaviour : public NativeBehaviour { A_REGISTER(NewNative_Behaviour, NativeBehaviour, Components) A_PROPERTIES( A_PROPERTYEX(Transform *, myTransform, NewNative_Behaviour::myTransform, NewNative_Behaviour::setMyTransform, "editor=Component") ) private: Transform *m_myTransform = nullptr; public: Transform *myTransform() const { return m_myTransform; } void setMyTransform(Transform *transform) { m_myTransform = transform; }
};
class NewAngelBehaviour : Behaviour { Transform @myTransform = null; // Use this to initialize behaviour void start() override { // Implementation here }
};
Note that in C++ code, an extended property is added. In this property, you can specify additional metadata as a string. This is necessary for the editor to understand the type of property it is working with. In this example, we indicate that a special editor type Component should be created.Available editor types:
Color
Component
Asset
Alignment
Axes
In the Properties window, it will look like this:<br><img alt="media/my_transform.png" src="scripting/media/my_transform.png" target="_self">Clicking the button in the property editor will bring up a special window that allows you to select the desired Object.<br><img alt="media/select_transform.png" src="scripting/media/select_transform.png" target="_self">]]></description><link>scripting/exporting_variables.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">scripting/exporting_variables.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 11:38:56 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="scripting/media/my_variable.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="scripting/media/my_variable.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[instantiating_prefabs]]></title><description><![CDATA[Prefabs can be very useful if you want to create complex Actors during gameplay. Instantiating game objects from Prefabs instead of creating game objects from scratch during runtime has several advantages:
Create a complex object with just one line instead of describing all components and their properties in detail in code.
Modify the Prefab in the Editor and get updates without needing to update the code.
Easily replace one Prefab with another without changing the code.
To instantiate a Prefab, you need to have a reference to it in your code. You can use a public variable to hold this reference. This variable will appear in the Properties editor, allowing you to assign the desired Prefab from the editor.C++:#include &lt;nativebehaviour.h&gt; class NewNative_Behaviour : public NativeBehaviour { A_REGISTER(NewNative_Behaviour, NativeBehaviour, Components) A_PROPERTIES( A_PROPERTYEX(Prefab *, myPrefab, NewNative_Behaviour::myPrefab, NewNative_Behaviour::setMyPrefab, "editor=Asset") ) private: Prefab *m_myPrefab = nullptr; public: void start() { Instantiate(m_myPrefab, Vector3(0, 0, 0), Quaternion()); } Prefab *myPrefab() const { return m_myPrefab; } void setMyPrefab(Prefab *prefab) { m_myPrefab = prefab; }
};
AngelScript:class NewAngelBehaviour : Behaviour { // Reference to the Prefab asset. Prefab @myPrefab = null; // Use this to initialize behaviour void start() override { // Creates an Actor at position (0, 0, 0) and no rotation. instantiate(myPrefab, Vector3(0, 0, 0), Quaternion()); }
};
Now, add this script to any Actor in the scene and assign a cube Prefab.<img alt="media/my_prefab.png" src="scripting/media/my_prefab.png" target="_self">Once you've assigned the Prefab, you can press Ctrl+G to start the simulation.If you've done everything correctly, a cube will appear in your scene.<br><img alt="media/instance_of_cube.png" src="scripting/media/instance_of_cube.png" target="_self">You can create many copies of a Prefab almost instantly. Using code to create structures is called Procedural Generation.Create a new script and name it Wall. The code below describes creating a wall from blocks.C++:#include &lt;nativebehaviour.h&gt; class Wall : public NativeBehaviour { A_REGISTER(NewNative_Behaviour, NativeBehaviour, Components) A_PROPERTIES( A_PROPERTYEX(Prefab *, blockPrefab, NewNative_Behaviour::blockPrefab, NewNative_Behaviour::setBlockPrefab, "editor=Asset") A_PROPERTY(int, width, NewNative_Behaviour::width, NewNative_Behaviour::setWidth), A_PROPERTY(int, height, NewNative_Behaviour::height, NewNative_Behaviour::setHeight) ) private: Prefab *m_blockPrefab = nullptr; int m_width = 10; int m_height = 5; public: void start() { for(int y=0; y&lt;height; ++y) { for(int x=0; x&lt;width; ++x) { Instantiate(m_myPrefab, Vector3(x + x * 0.1, y + y * 0.1, 0), Quaternion()); } } } Prefab *blockPrefab() const { return m_blockPrefab; } void setBlockPrefab(Prefab *prefab) { m_blockPrefab = prefab; } int width() const { return m_width; } void setWidth(int width) { m_width = width; } int height() const { return m_height; } void setHeight(int height) { m_height = height; }
};
AngelScript:class Wall : Behaviour { // Reference to the Prefab asset. Prefab @blockPrefab = null; int width = 10; int height = 5; void start() override { for(int y=0; y&lt;height; ++y) { for(int x=0; x&lt;width; ++x) { instantiate(blockPrefab, Vector3(x + x * 0.1, y + y * 0.1, 0), Quaternion()); } } }
};
Once you've set up your Actor and run the simulation, you'll see your wall on the screen:<br><img alt="media/wall_of_bricks.png" src="scripting/media/wall_of_bricks.png" target="_self">White Walkers shall not pass! The Seven Kingdoms can sleep peacefully now.]]></description><link>scripting/instantiating_prefabs.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">scripting/instantiating_prefabs.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 11:28:45 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="scripting/media/my_prefab.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="scripting/media/my_prefab.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[custom_modules]]></title><description><![CDATA[The VFX editor allows users to create custom modules that extend the editor's functionality by adding new types of particle modifiers, effects, and behaviors. Custom modules enable developers to create specialized visual effects tailored to the specific needs of the game.This guide outlines the steps required to create, implement, and integrate custom modules into the VFX editor.To create a custom module in the VFX editor, XML code is used to describe the behavior, parameters, and operations of the module. Below is an example of creating a module that initializes particles and sets their parameters (lifetime, position, color, rotation, and size).&lt;module name="Spawn/SampleModule" stage="update"&gt; &lt;options name="parameterMode"&gt; &lt;option value="Constant"/&gt; &lt;option value="Random"/&gt; &lt;/options&gt; &lt;params&gt; &lt;param name="lifetime" type="float" default="0" mode="parameterMode"/&gt; &lt;/params&gt; &lt;operations&gt; &lt;operation code="set" result="p.lifetime" arg0="lifetime"/&gt; &lt;/operations&gt;
&lt;/module&gt; module: This element specifies the name of the module, its type (e.g., "Spawn/SampleModule"), and the stage at which the module is applied (e.g., "spawn", "update", or "render").
options: Each module can contain different modes (e.g., "parameterMode") that determine how the module parameters are applied (e.g., constant or random value).
params: The parameters used to configure particle modifiers. Each parameter has a name, type, and mode (e.g., "lifetime").
operations: The operations performed on the parameters to configure the state of particles. For example, the "set" operation sets the value of a particle's parameter (e.g., "p.lifetime").
An interface to work with this module will be automatically generated in the editor, allowing users to modify the module's parameters through the parameters panel.The VFX editor supports the following operations for manipulating particle parameters:This operation sets the value of a parameter. For example, you can set the lifetime or position of a particle.Example:&lt;operation code="set" result="p.lifetime" arg0="lifetime"/&gt;
This operation performs addition on two values. It takes two input parameters and returns their sum.Example:&lt;operation code="add" result="p.position" arg0="p.position" arg1="0, 1, 0"/&gt;
This operation subtracts the second parameter from the first. It takes two input parameters and returns their difference.Example:&lt;operation code="sub" result="p.position" arg0="p.position" arg1="vec3"/&gt;
This operation multiplies two parameters. It takes two input parameters and returns their product.Example:&lt;operation code="mul" result="p.size" arg0="p.size" arg1="e.deltaTime"/&gt;
This operation divides the first parameter by the second. It takes two input parameters and returns their quotient.Example:&lt;operation code="div" result="p.size" arg0="p.size" arg1="2"/&gt;
Parameters used in custom modules can belong to different spaces. A space defines where and how the parameter values will be used.Parameters belonging to this space relate to the particle emitter itself. These parameters typically describe properties that affect all particles emitted by the emitter, such as emission speed or general effect settings.Example:&lt;operation code="multiply" result="p.size" arg0="p.size" arg1="e.deltaTime"/&gt;
Parameters in this space relate to individual particles. They control aspects such as size, color, position, and other properties that may change over time for each particle.Example:&lt;operation code="add" result="p.position" arg0="p.position" arg1="0, 1, 0"/&gt;
Parameters in this space relate to objects that can be rendered in the game. Typically, these parameters are only used in modules related to the "render" stage.Example:&lt;operation code="set" result="r.size" arg0="p.size.xy"/&gt;
Parameters in this space can change relative to the particle or emitter's local position. They are used as temporary storage for intermediate calculations for subsequent operations.Example:&lt;operation code="mul" result="vec3" arg0="p.velocity" arg1="e.deltaTime"/&gt;
&lt;operation code="add" result="p.position" arg0="p.position" arg1="vec3"/&gt;
To integrate a custom module into the editor, simply place the module in the Content Browser. Upon the next startup, the editor will automatically register it for use.Creating custom modules using XML allows you to extend the functionality of the VFX editor, creating unique visual effects for your game. By following the steps outlined, you can integrate new modules into the editor, configure their parameters, and optimize visual effects for specific tasks.]]></description><link>vfx/custom_modules.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">vfx/custom_modules.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 11:23:10 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[native_introspection]]></title><description><![CDATA[The introspection mechanism allows making Script bindings in transparent mode. Unfortunately, not all programming languages provide it out of the box. Thunder Engine uses a Meta Object approach to define a class structure to be able to retrieve this information at runtime.To make properties visible in the Editor and in Scripts, engine developers need to define a special construction inside a class body.In the example below, the developer defines all required fields:#include &lt;nativebehaviour.h&gt; class MyComponent : public NativeBehaviour { A_REGISTER(MyComponent, NativeBehaviour, Components) A_PROPERTIES( A_PROPERTY(int, speed, MyComponent::speed, MyComponent::setSpeed) ) A_METHODS( A_METHOD(void, MyComponent::jump) ) public: int speed() const { return m_speed; } void setSpeed(int speed) { m_speed = speed; } void jump(int force) { // Do jump code here } private: int m_speed = 0;
};
Thunder Engine's Meta-object system provides runtime type information like methods, properties, signals, and slots for inter-object communication.The meta-object system is based on two things:
The Object class provides a base class for objects that can take advantage of the meta-object system.
The A_REGISTER macro inside the private section of the class declaration is used to enable meta-object features, such as properties, signals, and slots.
In the provided example, the developer specified an introspection definition of the property speed:A_PROPERTIES ( A_PROPERTY(int, speed, MyComponent::speed, MyComponent::setSpeed)
)
Description of parameters for A_PROPERTY:
int - The return type of the property
speed - The name of the property that will be visible in the editor and in Scripts.
MyComponent::speed - The getter function of the property.
MyComponent::setSpeed - The setter function of the property. Note: If no public properties are provided in a native component, it is good practice to set A_NOPROPERTIES() in the class body. This will help avoid issues in introspection during inheritance.
In scripts, the developer can use not only properties but also call some functions for the component. In the example above, the developer has specified a jump method for introspection.A_METHODS( A_METHOD(void, MyComponent::jump)
)
Description of parameters for A_METHOD:
void - The return type of the method
MyComponent::jump - The function which will be registered. Note: If no public methods are provided in the native component, it is good practice to set A_NOMETHODS() in the class body. This will help avoid issues in introspection in the case of inheritance.
In gameplay programming, if one object changes, we often want another object to be notified. Signals and slots are used for communication between objects. The signals and slots are made possible by the Thunder introspection system.#include &lt;nativebehaviour.h&gt; class MyComponent : public NativeBehaviour { A_REGISTER(MyComponent, NativeBehaviour, Components) A_METHODS( A_SLOT(MyComponent::slot), A_SIGNAL(MyComponent::signal) ) public: void slot(int value) { // Make reaction on signal here } void signal(int value);
};
To connect objects, we need to call the connect function.Example:MyComponent component1;
MyComponent component2; connect(&amp;component1, _SIGNAL(signal(int)), &amp;component2, _SLOT(slot(int)));
In this code, we connect the signal from the object component1 with a slot in object component2. This means when the signal of object component1 is emitted, the slot of object component2 will be called.Connection rules:
The signature of a signal must match the signature of the receiving slot.
The signal can be connected to another signal to relay the event.
To emit a signal, we need to call:component1.emitSignal(_SIGNAL(signal(int)), 5); // 5 is the value of the signal argument
]]></description><link>scripting/native_introspection.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">scripting/native_introspection.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 11:23:09 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[editor]]></title><description><![CDATA[The VFX editor is a tool designed for creating and editing visual effects (VFX) in the game engine. Using this editor, you can create particle effects, lighting, shadows, animations, and other graphical elements that enhance the visual experience of the game.This documentation is intended for users who want to learn how to use the VFX editor to create, configure, and optimize visual effects in their games.<img alt="media/editor.png" src="vfx/media/editor.png" target="_self">The editor consists of several key areas:
Workspace: The area where VFX are visualized and edited, allowing you to configure and preview the effect in real time.
Parameter Editor: A panel located next to the workspace, where you can adjust the parameters of each particle modifier. Here, you can configure properties such as particle emission, trajectory, size, speed, and lifetime.
Preview Window: The area where you can preview the effect in real time. The Preview Window updates as you change the parameters, allowing you to immediately see the results.
In the editor, effects are represented as a cascade of particle modifiers, which allow you to fine-tune every aspect of the effect.
Go to the Content Browser.
Right-click and select Visual Effect from the context menu.<br>
<img alt="media/context_menu.png" src="vfx/media/context_menu.png" target="_self">
Confirm the creation. The new effect will appear in the Content Browser and will be available for further editing.<br>
<img alt="media/new_effect.png" src="vfx/media/new_effect.png" target="_self">
An effect consists of a series of modifiers that control different aspects of particle behavior. The cascade of modifiers allows you to configure:
Particle Emission: Set the quantity and frequency of particle generation.
Motion Trajectory: Define the direction and speed of the particles' movement.
Particle Lifetime: Specify how long each particle lasts.
Particle Size and Textures: Configure the appearance, including textures, transparency and other visual properties.
Each modifier can be adjusted using settings available in the Parameter Editor.These modifiers can be divided into three types:
Spawn - Modifier applied when a new particle is created:
These modifiers define the initial properties of a particle, such as its position, velocity, and other starting attributes when the particle is spawned.
Update - Modifier applied to update the particle state every frame:
These modifiers are responsible for changing the state of the particle over time, affecting its movement, size, color, and other dynamic properties during its lifetime.
Render - Modifier responsible for rendering the particle:
These modifiers control how the particle is drawn or rendered, including its appearance, texture, and any other visual characteristics that are applied during its display.
Each modifier can be adjusted using the settings available in the Parameter Editor.Modifiers in the cascade control various aspects of particle behavior and their interaction with the environment. Properly configuring the modifiers is essential for achieving the desired visual effect. Adding a Modifier
To add a new modifier, click on the Add Modificator button in Properties and select one of the available modifier types.<br>
<img alt="media/add_modificator.png" src="vfx/media/add_modificator.png" target="_self">
Some of the available modifiers: Add Velocity – to modify the particle speed.
Rotation Rate – to control the particle rotation angle.
Color Scale – to smoothly change the color of the particles from birth to death.
Size Scale – to modify the size of the particles over time. Configuring Modifier Parameters
After adding a modifier, you can adjust its parameters in the Parameter Editor. Depending on the modifier type, different settings will be available. For example: For the Velocity modifier, you can set the speed and direction.
For Color Scale, you can select the initial and final particle colors, as well as the duration of the color change. Previewing Changes
After adding and configuring the modifiers, you can immediately see the result in the Preview window. This will help you assess the impact of each change in real-time and fine-tune the parameters to achieve the desired outcome. Removing a Modifier
To remove a modifier, click on the "X" button in the Properties window. Removing the modifier will not affect other elements of the effect.<br>
<img alt="media/delete_modificator.png" src="vfx/media/delete_modificator.png" target="_self"> By following these steps, you can efficiently add and configure modifiers in the cascade to create complex and realistic visual effects.]]></description><link>vfx/editor.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">vfx/editor.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 11:11:21 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="vfx/media/editor.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="vfx/media/editor.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[add_modificator]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="vfx/media/add_modificator.png" target="_self">]]></description><link>vfx/media/add_modificator.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">vfx/media/add_modificator.png</guid><pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 15:17:14 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="vfx/media/add_modificator.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="vfx/media/add_modificator.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[editor]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="vfx/media/editor.png" target="_self">]]></description><link>vfx/media/editor.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">vfx/media/editor.png</guid><pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 14:18:14 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="vfx/media/editor.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="vfx/media/editor.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[delete_modificator]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="vfx/media/delete_modificator.png" target="_self">]]></description><link>vfx/media/delete_modificator.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">vfx/media/delete_modificator.png</guid><pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 07:18:53 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="vfx/media/delete_modificator.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="vfx/media/delete_modificator.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[new_effect]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="vfx/media/new_effect.png" target="_self">]]></description><link>vfx/media/new_effect.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">vfx/media/new_effect.png</guid><pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 05:34:33 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="vfx/media/new_effect.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="vfx/media/new_effect.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[context_menu]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="vfx/media/context_menu.png" target="_self">]]></description><link>vfx/media/context_menu.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">vfx/media/context_menu.png</guid><pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 05:32:11 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="vfx/media/context_menu.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="vfx/media/context_menu.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[wall_of_bricks]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="scripting/media/wall_of_bricks.png" target="_self">]]></description><link>scripting/media/wall_of_bricks.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">scripting/media/wall_of_bricks.png</guid><pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2024 15:17:42 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="scripting/media/wall_of_bricks.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="scripting/media/wall_of_bricks.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[instance_of_cube]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="scripting/media/instance_of_cube.png" target="_self">]]></description><link>scripting/media/instance_of_cube.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">scripting/media/instance_of_cube.png</guid><pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2024 14:56:03 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="scripting/media/instance_of_cube.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="scripting/media/instance_of_cube.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[my_prefab]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="scripting/media/my_prefab.png" target="_self">]]></description><link>scripting/media/my_prefab.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">scripting/media/my_prefab.png</guid><pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2024 14:50:59 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="scripting/media/my_prefab.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="scripting/media/my_prefab.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[select_transform]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="scripting/media/select_transform.png" target="_self">]]></description><link>scripting/media/select_transform.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">scripting/media/select_transform.png</guid><pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2024 07:56:12 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="scripting/media/select_transform.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="scripting/media/select_transform.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[my_transform]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="scripting/media/my_transform.png" target="_self">]]></description><link>scripting/media/my_transform.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">scripting/media/my_transform.png</guid><pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2024 07:51:42 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="scripting/media/my_transform.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="scripting/media/my_transform.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[my_variable]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="scripting/media/my_variable.png" target="_self">]]></description><link>scripting/media/my_variable.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">scripting/media/my_variable.png</guid><pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2024 07:01:38 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="scripting/media/my_variable.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="scripting/media/my_variable.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[hello_world]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="scripting/media/hello_world.png" target="_self">]]></description><link>scripting/media/hello_world.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">scripting/media/hello_world.png</guid><pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2024 14:01:45 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="scripting/media/hello_world.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="scripting/media/hello_world.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[new_component]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="scripting/media/new_component.png" target="_self">]]></description><link>scripting/media/new_component.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">scripting/media/new_component.png</guid><pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2024 13:58:15 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="scripting/media/new_component.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="scripting/media/new_component.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[add_component]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="scripting/media/add_component.png" target="_self">]]></description><link>scripting/media/add_component.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">scripting/media/add_component.png</guid><pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2024 13:55:28 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="scripting/media/add_component.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="scripting/media/add_component.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[new_script]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="scripting/media/new_script.png" target="_self">]]></description><link>scripting/media/new_script.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">scripting/media/new_script.png</guid><pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2024 13:29:44 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="scripting/media/new_script.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="scripting/media/new_script.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[actor_scheme]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="scripting/media/actor_scheme.png" target="_self">]]></description><link>scripting/media/actor_scheme.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">scripting/media/actor_scheme.png</guid><pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2024 11:45:12 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="scripting/media/actor_scheme.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="scripting/media/actor_scheme.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[game_cycle]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="scripting/media/game_cycle.png" target="_self">]]></description><link>scripting/media/game_cycle.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">scripting/media/game_cycle.png</guid><pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2024 11:44:55 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="scripting/media/game_cycle.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="scripting/media/game_cycle.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[hierarhy]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="scripting/media/hierarhy.png" target="_self">]]></description><link>scripting/media/hierarhy.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">scripting/media/hierarhy.png</guid><pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2024 11:44:27 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="scripting/media/hierarhy.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="scripting/media/hierarhy.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[signals_slots]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="scripting/media/signals_slots.png" target="_self">]]></description><link>scripting/media/signals_slots.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">scripting/media/signals_slots.png</guid><pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2024 11:40:08 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="scripting/media/signals_slots.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="scripting/media/signals_slots.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[qbs_path]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="editor/media/qbs_path.png" target="_self">]]></description><link>editor/media/qbs_path.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">editor/media/qbs_path.png</guid><pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 10:28:48 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="editor/media/qbs_path.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="editor/media/qbs_path.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[plugin_manager]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="editor/media/plugin_manager.png" target="_self">]]></description><link>editor/media/plugin_manager.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">editor/media/plugin_manager.png</guid><pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 08:19:45 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="editor/media/plugin_manager.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="editor/media/plugin_manager.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[editor_preferences]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="editor/media/editor_preferences.png" target="_self">]]></description><link>editor/media/editor_preferences.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">editor/media/editor_preferences.png</guid><pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 08:18:02 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="editor/media/editor_preferences.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="editor/media/editor_preferences.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[content]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="editor/media/content.png" target="_self">]]></description><link>editor/media/content.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">editor/media/content.png</guid><pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 08:17:41 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="editor/media/content.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="editor/media/content.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[asset_creation]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="editor/media/asset_creation.gif" target="_self">]]></description><link>editor/media/asset_creation.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">editor/media/asset_creation.gif</guid><pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 06:15:17 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="editor/media/asset_creation.gif" length="0" type="image/gif"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="editor/media/asset_creation.gif"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[add_component]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="editor/media/add_component.png" target="_self">]]></description><link>editor/media/add_component.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">editor/media/add_component.png</guid><pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2023 16:56:49 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="editor/media/add_component.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="editor/media/add_component.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[asset_properties]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="editor/media/asset_properties.png" target="_self">]]></description><link>editor/media/asset_properties.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">editor/media/asset_properties.png</guid><pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2023 16:56:49 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="editor/media/asset_properties.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="editor/media/asset_properties.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[editor_tools]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="editor/media/editor_tools.png" target="_self">]]></description><link>editor/media/editor_tools.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">editor/media/editor_tools.png</guid><pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2023 16:56:49 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="editor/media/editor_tools.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="editor/media/editor_tools.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[hierarchy]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="editor/media/hierarchy.png" target="_self">]]></description><link>editor/media/hierarchy.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">editor/media/hierarchy.png</guid><pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2023 16:56:49 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="editor/media/hierarchy.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="editor/media/hierarchy.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[move]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="editor/media/move.gif" target="_self">]]></description><link>editor/media/move.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">editor/media/move.gif</guid><pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2023 16:56:49 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="editor/media/move.gif" length="0" type="image/gif"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="editor/media/move.gif"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[properties]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="editor/media/properties.png" target="_self">]]></description><link>editor/media/properties.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">editor/media/properties.png</guid><pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2023 16:56:49 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="editor/media/properties.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="editor/media/properties.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[rotate]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="editor/media/rotate.gif" target="_self">]]></description><link>editor/media/rotate.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">editor/media/rotate.gif</guid><pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2023 16:56:49 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="editor/media/rotate.gif" length="0" type="image/gif"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="editor/media/rotate.gif"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[scale]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="editor/media/scale.gif" target="_self">]]></description><link>editor/media/scale.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">editor/media/scale.gif</guid><pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2023 16:56:49 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="editor/media/scale.gif" length="0" type="image/gif"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="editor/media/scale.gif"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[viewport]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="editor/media/viewport.png" target="_self">]]></description><link>editor/media/viewport.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">editor/media/viewport.png</guid><pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2023 16:56:49 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="editor/media/viewport.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="editor/media/viewport.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[workspace]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="editor/media/workspace.png" target="_self">]]></description><link>editor/media/workspace.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">editor/media/workspace.png</guid><pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2023 16:56:49 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="editor/media/workspace.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="editor/media/workspace.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[success]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="editor/media/success.png" target="_self">]]></description><link>editor/media/success.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">editor/media/success.png</guid><pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2022 17:36:28 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="editor/media/success.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="editor/media/success.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[build_project]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="editor/media/build_project.png" target="_self">]]></description><link>editor/media/build_project.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">editor/media/build_project.png</guid><pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2022 08:16:20 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="editor/media/build_project.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="editor/media/build_project.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[create_object]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="editor/media/create_object.gif" target="_self">]]></description><link>editor/media/create_object.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">editor/media/create_object.gif</guid><pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2022 12:46:56 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="editor/media/create_object.gif" length="0" type="image/gif"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="editor/media/create_object.gif"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[properties]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="scripting/media/properties.png" target="_self">]]></description><link>scripting/media/properties.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">scripting/media/properties.png</guid><pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2022 08:19:09 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="scripting/media/properties.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="scripting/media/properties.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[import]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="basics/media/import.png" target="_self">]]></description><link>basics/media/import.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">basics/media/import.png</guid><pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2020 06:27:11 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="basics/media/import.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="basics/media/import.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[new]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="basics/media/new.png" target="_self">]]></description><link>basics/media/new.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">basics/media/new.png</guid><pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2020 06:24:01 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="basics/media/new.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="basics/media/new.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[welcome]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="basics/media/welcome.png" target="_self">]]></description><link>basics/media/welcome.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">basics/media/welcome.png</guid><pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 11:20:07 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="basics/media/welcome.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="basics/media/welcome.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>